<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meetings on Legogoa Axi0m</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/tags/meetings/</link><description>Recent content in meetings on Legogoa Axi0m</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/tags/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Session on Engineering Notebook by Mr Ashwin Shah</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog9/</guid><description>On 4 January 2023,Mr Ashwin Shah, the mentor of team Sigma and many other FTC teams took a session to advise us on how to maintain the engineering notebook.
He explained to us that the engineering notebook is one of the most important aspects of advancing in the First Tech Challenge as it is the basis on which the judges would judge our work.
He advised us on how we should devote 3 to 4 days to our engineering notebook before beginning our builds by dividing ourselves into teams under the categories of engineering, outreach and fundraising and collect information from each group and filling it into a predefined template.</description></item><item><title>Github sessions</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog3/</guid><description>We were thinking of building a website which includes everyone&amp;rsquo;s collaboration. Our team coach Saieesh Sir introduced us to GitHub and planned training sessions.
Yesterday was our first training session on GitHub. In GitHub, everyone in a team can collaborate. It includes all the records of how the team had constructed a website i.e.how many have contributed. It also shows when and what changes a teammate has created on the website.</description></item><item><title>First meeting session</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>On Sunday, the 4th of December Team Legogoa Axiom gathered at the house of our mentor, Saieesh Gandhi to discuss and understand the format, scoring system and components of the game.
With excellent presentations made by Viraj, Aniket, Sai Pranav and Vighnesh, helped us to understand rules of the game and triggered our thinking about our strategy in the tournament.
We are also very excited that the parts will be arriving in a few days time and we can build and program our robot soon.</description></item></channel></rss>