<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>outreach on Legogoa Axi0m</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/tags/outreach/</link><description>Recent content in outreach on Legogoa Axi0m</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/tags/outreach/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Awareness Session at Government Schools</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog10/</guid><description>I conducted a workshop to create awareness about various coding-robotics competitions held at the international/national/state level. It was a 3-hour workshop. The students from grade 5 to grade 10 attended the workshop. I conducted it at Progress High School (Government School) free of cost!
The students were very excited to attend. I got a chance to clear up various doubts. They also had a fear of learning robotics. After attending this workshop, this fear was gone.</description></item><item><title>Workshops</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog8/</guid><description>Ponda Workshop
Our Team comprising of Venkatesh Dempo, Shounak Hede and Dhruv Desai (VSD) conducted a workshop on “Explore the World of Robotics” for 12 students on 14th December 2022 at 3:30 pm in Ponda. We conducted this workshop in a school called as Vidhya Vruddhi school. The workshop was conducted to raise funds for a competition called FTC (First Tech Challenge). A competition for students between grades 7-12. We registered 12 students of age group 7 to 13 years charging them Rs 500 per head.</description></item><item><title>Lego Workshop by Saipranav Gandhi</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog7/</guid><description>As part of the First Tech Challenge competition&amp;rsquo;s outreach activity, Team Legogoa Axi0m conducted a two-day Lego robotics workshop at the Innovation hub, Goa Science centre. 12 participants attended the workshop, and Sai Pranav Gandhi commenced the session by explaining what robots are, how they function, and what sensors and motors are? Shounak Hede explained how to code a Robot and also gave a brief introduction to FTC. All the participants were split into 4 teams, each consisting of 3 members, and they started building the basic EV3 Robot.</description></item><item><title>Outreach activity at Mushtifund High School</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog5/</guid><description>We (Aniket Bhatikar and Samihan Pangam) conducted a workshop on 21 and 22 December 2022, &amp;lsquo;Basic Electronics and Robotics&amp;rsquo;, as a part of a fundraising initiative. This workshop was our first outreach activity. Our teammates Venkatesh, Shounak and Dhruv have also conducted various outreach activities across Goa.
We conducted this workshop, especially for Mushtifund High School students. Our fee was Rs.500 per student. A total of 6 students had registered. We taught them the basics of electronics like LEDs, breadboards, Buzzers, motor drivers etc.</description></item><item><title>Fundraising initiatives</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>In the true spirit of FIRST, three team members of Legogoa Axi0m 22855 decided to combine outreach and raising funds into one event and they did it successfully by conducting a nominally paid robotics workshop called “Explore the World of Robotics.
The team members, Venkatesh Dempo, Shounak Hede and Dhruv Desai (aka Team VSD) conducted their first workshop on 4th December, 2022 at Goa&amp;rsquo;s capital city of Panaji and their second workshop on 8th December, 2022 at Margao.</description></item></channel></rss>