<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs 📃 on Legogoa Axi0m</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs 📃 on Legogoa Axi0m</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ftc workshop</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog15/</guid><description>This 3-day workshop was hosted by Legogoa as a part of their project that they&amp;rsquo;re currently working on - Project FTC.
The 3-day workshop: This was a workshop wherein members of Team Sigma flew down from Mumbai to help Legogoa with their robot build and other aspects of the competition. Additionally, children from a nearby school were invited to observe and they gained experience
The First Day: The 3-day workshop started off great - team Sigma arrived from the airport at the venue of this workshop - Nagali Hills.</description></item><item><title>3 days Ftc workshop</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog14/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog14/</guid><description>Day-1: The 3-day workshop started off great - team Sigma arrived from the airport at the venue of this workshop - Venkatesh’s house in Nagalli Hills. We welcomed them and they were ecstatic to watch our robot in action and noted all the areas that could be improved. We worked on the robot till about 7 in the evening and that’s when the team-building exercises started where we played a few games which helped us get to know each other better.</description></item><item><title>Ftc workshop</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog13/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog13/</guid><description>The three day FTC workshop has been highly successful at multiple fronts. The team secured advice from a senior team about the gaps in the strategy and also improvements in design of the robot. We also got a good team bonding experience due to sessions by Expert Karuna Satardekar We managed good visibility with the visit of Honble Minister for Tourism and IT visiting us as Chief Guest. We got Fantastic media visibility at state level due to wide press coverage.</description></item><item><title>Hardware Session</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog12/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog12/</guid><description>On 10th January, we met physically at our mentor’s house. Venkatesh , Sai Pranav and Avneesh were present.
Venkatesh and Avneesh, were working on fixing the robot. That was tightening the tyres along with the axcel, the bearing and the gears. We did this as the tyres were loose and were shaking and could make the robot unstable. This was a very tedious process. Venkatesh and I failed multiple times before we managed to get it right.</description></item><item><title>Build session</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog11/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog11/</guid><description>On Sunday the 8th Jan, we met physically at our mentor&amp;rsquo;s house. Viraj and Vighnesh conducted a session for the team members to learn about pull requests. Aditya, Aniket and Dhruv attended the session. Aniket even created a pull request regarding this outreach activity at Progress High School.
For the first building part of the chassis, the three of us were Sai Pranav, Viraj and Druv. We realised we did not have enough parts to make the strafer chassis last time because we had opened the assembly manual for the strafer chassis v5, but our kit was that of v4.</description></item><item><title>Awareness Session at Government Schools</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog10/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog10/</guid><description>I conducted a workshop to create awareness about various coding-robotics competitions held at the international/national/state level. It was a 3-hour workshop. The students from grade 5 to grade 10 attended the workshop. I conducted it at Progress High School (Government School) free of cost!
The students were very excited to attend. I got a chance to clear up various doubts. They also had a fear of learning robotics. After attending this workshop, this fear was gone.</description></item><item><title>Session on Engineering Notebook by Mr Ashwin Shah</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog9/</guid><description>On 4 January 2023,Mr Ashwin Shah, the mentor of team Sigma and many other FTC teams took a session to advise us on how to maintain the engineering notebook.
He explained to us that the engineering notebook is one of the most important aspects of advancing in the First Tech Challenge as it is the basis on which the judges would judge our work.
He advised us on how we should devote 3 to 4 days to our engineering notebook before beginning our builds by dividing ourselves into teams under the categories of engineering, outreach and fundraising and collect information from each group and filling it into a predefined template.</description></item><item><title>Workshops</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog8/</guid><description>Ponda Workshop
Our Team comprising of Venkatesh Dempo, Shounak Hede and Dhruv Desai (VSD) conducted a workshop on “Explore the World of Robotics” for 12 students on 14th December 2022 at 3:30 pm in Ponda. We conducted this workshop in a school called as Vidhya Vruddhi school. The workshop was conducted to raise funds for a competition called FTC (First Tech Challenge). A competition for students between grades 7-12. We registered 12 students of age group 7 to 13 years charging them Rs 500 per head.</description></item><item><title>Lego Workshop by Saipranav Gandhi</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog7/</guid><description>As part of the First Tech Challenge competition&amp;rsquo;s outreach activity, Team Legogoa Axi0m conducted a two-day Lego robotics workshop at the Innovation hub, Goa Science centre. 12 participants attended the workshop, and Sai Pranav Gandhi commenced the session by explaining what robots are, how they function, and what sensors and motors are? Shounak Hede explained how to code a Robot and also gave a brief introduction to FTC. All the participants were split into 4 teams, each consisting of 3 members, and they started building the basic EV3 Robot.</description></item><item><title>Visit to Additive Manufacturing Hub</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog6/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog6/</guid><description>On 28 December 2022, FTC Team LegoGoa Axiom became the first customer for Additive manufacturing hub inaugurated at the IT Department in Altinho this year.
Due to the need for high precision and efficient parts, FTC Team LegoGoa Axiom requested AM hub to 3D print the claw which will be used to grab and lift cones as part of the required task for First Tech Challenge.
At the lab the staff present there explained the process of 3D printing to the students and also provided knowledge regarding the difference between the fusion type 3D printers and additive type 3D printers, the process of plastic mold injection and the different types of materials with which 3d printers work.</description></item><item><title>Outreach activity at Mushtifund High School</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog5/</guid><description>We (Aniket Bhatikar and Samihan Pangam) conducted a workshop on 21 and 22 December 2022, &amp;lsquo;Basic Electronics and Robotics&amp;rsquo;, as a part of a fundraising initiative. This workshop was our first outreach activity. Our teammates Venkatesh, Shounak and Dhruv have also conducted various outreach activities across Goa.
We conducted this workshop, especially for Mushtifund High School students. Our fee was Rs.500 per student. A total of 6 students had registered. We taught them the basics of electronics like LEDs, breadboards, Buzzers, motor drivers etc.</description></item><item><title>Having fun</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog4/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog4/</guid><description>Having fun is primary at Team Legogoa meetups and we had celebrations by cutting of a cake by the birthday boy Shounak. We had a twist with the cake cutting as shounak used a slider with a knife to cut the robot themed cake.
^We also had a serious monkey storming session as evident from the picture.
We were thinking of building a website which includes everyone&amp;rsquo;s collaboration. Our team coach Saieesh Sir introduced us to GitHub and planned training sessions.</description></item><item><title>Github sessions</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog3/</guid><description>We were thinking of building a website which includes everyone&amp;rsquo;s collaboration. Our team coach Saieesh Sir introduced us to GitHub and planned training sessions.
Yesterday was our first training session on GitHub. In GitHub, everyone in a team can collaborate. It includes all the records of how the team had constructed a website i.e.how many have contributed. It also shows when and what changes a teammate has created on the website.</description></item><item><title>Fundraising initiatives</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog2/</guid><description>In the true spirit of FIRST, three team members of Legogoa Axi0m 22855 decided to combine outreach and raising funds into one event and they did it successfully by conducting a nominally paid robotics workshop called “Explore the World of Robotics.
The team members, Venkatesh Dempo, Shounak Hede and Dhruv Desai (aka Team VSD) conducted their first workshop on 4th December, 2022 at Goa&amp;rsquo;s capital city of Panaji and their second workshop on 8th December, 2022 at Margao.</description></item><item><title>First meeting session</title><link>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://legogoa-axiom.github.io/posts/blog1/</guid><description>On Sunday, the 4th of December Team Legogoa Axiom gathered at the house of our mentor, Saieesh Gandhi to discuss and understand the format, scoring system and components of the game.
With excellent presentations made by Viraj, Aniket, Sai Pranav and Vighnesh, helped us to understand rules of the game and triggered our thinking about our strategy in the tournament.
We are also very excited that the parts will be arriving in a few days time and we can build and program our robot soon.</description></item></channel></rss>